If you are thinking of taking a health insurance policy from HDFC Ergo, then there are high
chances are that you will take Optima Secure Plan. Why is it so?
It is the best selling plan of the company and along with it, it also has great features like Secure Benefit Plus and
Protect Benefit but when it comes to using these features,
we have very limited knowledge  about that and this is because
When we buy health insurance policies, we are told three or four such
lines as a sales trick which our ears want to hear. After that, neither do we ask any question
nor does any doubt arise in our mind.
The truth is revealed only when we file a claim in this policy in future.
then these insurance companies stand in front of us with a long list of terms and conditions.
Now the complete claim is rejected or a huge amount is deducted from this claim, nothing can be done !
We should have paid attention to these things on terms and conditions
when we were busy listening to our favorite lines.
In the Pol Khol series, we have brought for you different health insurance plans
and the mysterious features inside them, those features which have a lot
of terms and conditions are explained in very simple language.
And in today's video we will reveal the benefits of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure's
Automatic Restoration benefit. We will understand this benefit in detail,
Will understand those terms and conditions which should be mentioned while taking this plan.
So what's the delay . Let's start this video quickly !
The first question  is that - When will the  restoration benefit be activated in the HDFC Ergo Optima Secure plan ?
When our entire sum insured and cumulative bonus will be exhausted
or if some amount is partially used in any claim then this amount
will be restored ?
The insurance company says about this.
The company shall instantly add 100% of the base sum insured under this benefit in the event of an
admissible claim during the policy year due to which sum insured was Partially or
completely exhausted. It means that whether some money from your sum insured has been used for any
treatment or your entire sum
insured has been exhausted, in both the cases
your restoration benefit will be active up to 100% of sum insured
but some terms and conditions are applicable on this automatic retortion
benefit,
This Pol Khol series is focused on revealing these terms, so let's know What are the terms & conditions?
The first condition is :
The company says that the benefit of automatic restoration
can be availed once in a year. Suppose I have a policy of ₹ 10 lakh and once
I took some treatment in which all these ₹ 10 lakh is spent or 4-5 lakh is spent
then the amount will be restored once upto 100% of the sum insured
unless If it is written in your policy that it is unlimited times, then this will happen after every admitted claim.
That is, whatever claim the insurance company approves, after that whatever expenses you have incurred,
the insured amount will be restored up to 100% of the sum insured,
In the standard policy, you will get automatic restoration benefit only once a year.
But if you take unlimited times as an add-on, then you will get automatic restoration benefit on every admissible claim.
whether it is partially used or the entire sum insured is exhausted.
The second condition is
Now suppose I took a policy and I used some money in it. This will be restored
This amount can be used for the subsequent claim means the next claim
You cannot use the restoration benefit money in the same claim in which this money has been spent.
You can use the restoration benefit money in the subsequent claim.
That means you can use the restoration amount in the next claim.
The third condition says
The company says that this amount which will be restored
Which you will get again, you can use it
For treatment in only two sections
What are those
Section b1 is inpatient hospitalization
That is, when a patient policy holder is admitted for treatment, then that patient can use
the money of restoration benefit can be used and section B 2.3, what is this ?
This is the protect benefit i.e. non
medical items i.e. consumable items
The amount of restoration benefit can be used to compensate for inpatient hospitalization as well as
can also be used to compensate the protect benefit i.e. non medical items
The use is restricted to these two sections. The fourth condition says
The company says that under our Optima Secure plan, within any year
The claim that comes from you cannot exceed this amount. What is that amount
Your basic sum insured, apart from this, if there is any cumulative bonus in your policy, it should be added to it
If there is any plus benefit in your policy, it should be added
And finally the secure benefit which is equal to the sum insured After adding all these four
The amount that comes by adding them, a single claim cannot exceed this amount and if
You have seen the review video of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure, then in that
we have also explained how your sum
insured, the coverage amount
after two-three renewals becomes four times, it happens after adding these four benefits
and clubbing them. Here is the important thing you should notice
There is no mention of restoration benefit
Because the amount of restoration benefit is
and cannot be added separately. Fifth
Condition is
means any policy holder
who has already taken a claim and has used the sum in the policy
during treatment, he can also use this restoration benefit
amount and if there is any other policy holder then he can
can do so. Why is this mentioned here
because in many plans this condition
is there in restoration benefit that if If you have taken any claim earlier in the whole year
So now either you will not be able to use the restoration benefit or you will have to wait for some
time, there is no such condition here, whether you have taken the claim earlier
or not, if you are a policy holder then you can use the restoration money
Now friends, let us understand the sixth condition also here it is written in the policy wording that
It means the illness for which your sum insured has been used earlier by any policy holder
This restoration benefit money can also be used for treatment of the same illness also.
In many plans there is a condition here that you cannot take treatment for the same illness
Here you can take treatment for the same illness as well as for a different illness
different diseases and different treatments for them this coverage is also there.
The seventh condition comes
The Restoration amount you get when
Basic Sum Insured gets exhausted either partially or fully, if it is not used further
in the whole year, then it cannot be carried forward. You already know it
that sum insured can be carried forward which you get separately from the basic sum insured
such as Cumulative Bonus Plus benefit, you can carry that forward
You get it in the next year also and as it is you get it continuously But
Because this restoration benefit only restores your basic sum insured
And next year you are going to get a completely new sum insured, so restoration
benefit will works on year on year basis and all these terms and conditions
will be applicable. We cannot carry forward or accumulate the remaining restoration benefit amount.
Final condition is:
A family floater policy is the one in which you have a sum insured
the entire family is covered under this sum insured i.e. whatever your sum insured is ₹ 10 lakh
20 lakhs. The entire family can use the money from this single sum insured.
If there is no separate sum insured then the family. If the policy is floater then
The Restoration benefit is that the amount that is restored to you will also be on a floater basis
Each policy holder will not get a separate sum insured for each member. This will also be
On a floater basis, there will be a sum insured for the restoration amount and from this the entire family
can use the money for the next treatment
and along with this the rest of the terms
and conditions those will also be applicable. Now here HDFC Ergo Optima Secure
While taking the plan keep one thing in mind that Automatic restoration is available only once a year
under the standard policy
And if you want to take it unlimited times
As mentioned in the first condition
For which in your policy schedule
Unlimited times should be written only then You will get these unlimited times, so for this
You have to take a separate unlimited restoration addon. So friends, today we have exposed the
about the automatic restoration benefit of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure Plan
The insurance company has written every term and condition in its policy
in very clear words, but the only difference is that today we have understood them
well. If you liked the information and understood it, then
to show love and support, you can like the video and where necessary
Do share this video, if anyone
has HDFC ERGO Optima Secure Plan
If you have friends or clients, then
do share this information with them so that
They can know the correct use of automatic restoration and other terms and conditions
In the next video of Pol Khel series, what feature of which plan you want to expose ?
Let us know in the comments section. Other videos of Pol Khel series To watch
You can click here
You will get the full playlist of my videos
Myself Harvinder Singh, now I take your permission. I will meet you in the next video
Take care of yourself, stay happy and
stay healthy, Jai Hind